<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2026 Digital Grease -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.digitalgrease.FauxxDesktop</id>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0-only</project_license>

  <name>Fauxx Desktop Companion</name>
  <summary>Generate realistic decoy web activity to pollute data-broker profiles</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Fauxx Desktop Companion is a privacy command center for the desktop: it
      generates realistic decoy web activity through synthetic personas to
      pollute the profiles that data brokers and ad-tech build about you. It is
      the cross-device companion to the Fauxx Android app, sharing the same
      persona model so a household can present one coherent, deliberately
      misleading picture across phone and desktop.
    </p>
    <p>
      It is decoy-only and local-first by design: it never touches your real
      accounts, never logs in anywhere, sends no telemetry, and keeps all state
      in an encrypted store on your own machine.
    </p>
    <p>What it does:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Coherent synthetic personas drawn from a real US Census ACS-PUMS distribution.</li>
      <li>A real-browser decoy that drives a dedicated, isolated Chromium profile over the DevTools Protocol.</li>
      <li>Cross-device coordination: pair with the phone over the LAN to run or rotate the same persona.</li>
      <li>Per-persona egress (proxy, Tor, VPN) and DNS strategy, fail-closed so it never falls back to your real IP.</li>
      <li>Measurement: KL-divergence and per-category drift, plus CSV/JSON/PDF efficacy snapshots.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      The real-browser decoy uses your system-installed Chromium at run time.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">net.digitalgrease.FauxxDesktop.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/digital-grease/fauxx-desktop</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/digital-grease/fauxx-desktop/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/digital-grease/fauxx-desktop</url>

  <developer id="net.digitalgrease">
    <name>Digital Grease</name>
  </developer>

  <provides>
    <binary>fauxx-desktop</binary>
  </provides>

  <categories>
    <category>Network</category>
    <category>Security</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>privacy</keyword>
    <keyword>tracking</keyword>
    <keyword>data-broker</keyword>
    <keyword>decoy</keyword>
    <keyword>persona</keyword>
    <keyword>topics</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-07-10">
      <description>
        <p>Adds a stable per-persona desktop device identity (user-agent and client hints) for the decoy browser.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
